到目前为止，您应该非常熟悉这个表达式。这是僵硬的身体
This expression should be pretty familiar to you by this point. This is the rigid body
串联机器人机械手的运动方程。我们有一个惯性词;科里奥利
equations of motion of a serial link robot manipulator. We have an inertia term; Coriolis
和向心词;重力项;机器人施加的扭矩;联合加速;和
and centripetal term; gravity term; the torque applied the robot; joint acceleration; and
关节速度。该表达式也称为逆
joint velocity. This expression is also known as the inverse
动力学。我们可以将其视为映射机器人Q，Q点的运动的函数
dynamics. We can think of it as a function that maps the motion of the robot Q, Q-dot
和Q点圆点，需要施加到机器人关节的扭矩。我们采取
and Q-dot-dot, to the torque that needs to be applied to the robots' joints. We take
这个表达并重新安排它。我们最终得到了Q-dot-dot的表达式，我们
this expression and re-arrange it. We end up with an expression for Q-dot-dot, and we
关于时间可以集成Q点点得到Q点，联合速度我们可以
can integrate Q-dot-dot with respect to time to get Q-dot, the joint velocity and we can
再次整合它以获得联合位置。这组方程称为
integrate it again to get the joint position. This set of equations is referred to as the
前进动态。这是一个映射我们施加到机器人的扭矩的功能
forward dynamics. This is a function that maps the torque that we applied to the robot
到关节位置，速度和加速度。因此，这些前向动力学用于模拟
to the joint position, velocity and acceleration. So, these forward dynamics are used to simulate
机器人运动。如果我知道我将要应用于机器人操纵器的扭矩和力
robot motion. If I know the torques and forces that I'm going to apply to the robot manipulator
然后我可以计算Q，Q点和Q点点作为时间的函数。
and then I can compute Q, Q-dot and Q-dot-dot as a function of time.
让我们看看我们如何使用前向动力学来模拟复杂的运动
Let's have a look at how we can use the forward dynamics to simulate the motion of a complex
像PUMA560这样的6轴机器人。我将首先加载PUMA560的型号
6-axis robot like the PUMA 560. I'm going to start by loading a model of the PUMA 560
进入我的工作区，因为我们之前做了很多次，我将调用Simulink
into my workspace as we've done a number of times before and I'm going to invoke a Simulink
随机器人工具箱提供的模型，这就是它的样子。真是太棒了
model that is provided with the Robotics Toolbox, and this is what it looks like. It's quite
一个简单的模型。它包含一个没有库仑摩擦的机器人，并连接到动画
a simple model. It contains a robot with no Coulomb friction, and connected to an animation
或绘图块。机器人由零扭矩驱动。所以如果你想象一个机器人
or plotting block. And the robot is driven by zero torques. So if you imagine a robot
坐在一个正常的配置，我关掉所有的关节扭矩，机器人正在进行
sitting in a normal configuration and I turn off all the joint torque, the robot is going
在自重下崩溃。所以，我可以运行该模拟器，我们在这里看到
to collapse under its own weight. So, I can run that simulator and here we see
PUMA机器人在重力作用下坍塌，并且由于关节摩擦，能量
the PUMA robot and it's collapsing under gravity, and because of the joint friction, the energy
迅速消散，机器人处于向下指向的状态。
is rapidly dissipated and the robot is left in a downward pointing configuration.